Cemal Mingir

Front-End Developer & UI/UX Designer

cemalmingir.com

in linkedin.com/in/cemal-mingir

cemal.mingir@roylimited.co.uk

07597-728-958

🙀 github.com/mingirc



ABOUT ME

Solution-driven Developer & Designer adept at contributing to the highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience over 15+ years, meeting the highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, and speed. Developing by using SOLID principles and Design Patterns for reusable, extensible, and maintainable projects. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations, and databases.

EXPERIENCE

Developer & Designer @ Roy Limited 2020 - Present | Coventry, UK

- · Developing and designing web-based solutions.
- 8+ Projects deployed less than two years.
- From e-commerce to tailor-made applications, from logo and corporate identity design to front-end development are all in scope.
- Great at REST APIs and system integrations.
- Benefiting from SOLID principles and Design Patterns to create reusable, extensible, and maintainable projects.
- Git/Github for version control.
- Deep understanding APIs, REST API.

Full Stack Developer @ Freelance 2007 - 2020

- Developed and deployed more than 20+ different system-specific projects as freelancer for different types of companies.
- Detailed data flow system for call center, catalog system for store, online phone book for hospital, ecommerce websites, and company websites.
- HTML, CSS, ASP, and JavaScript were languages that had been used these days.

CERTIFICATES

- Responsive Web Design Certificate | freeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures | freeCodeCamp
- Front End Development Libraries | freeCodeCamp
- ∘ Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django | Udemy
- ∘ Build a Django eCommerce Web Application | Udemy
- An Advanced Django Ecommerce Web Application | Udemy
- ∘ SEO for Everyone DwordPress SEO Training | Udemy
- · Complete ASP.NET Web Development Training | Udemy

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Python, C#, CSS/Sass, HTML, SQL

Frameworks / Libraries

React, Redux, Angular, Django, .Net Core MVC, Formik, Yup, React-Hook-Form

Tools / Platforms

Git/Github, AWS, Bash, Word-press, MySQL, MSSQL, PortgreSQL

Design

Adobe XD, Illustrator, Photoshop, Figma, Balsamiq

EDUCATION

Bahcesehir University

2016-2017 | Istanbul Masters of Business Administration UK ENIC Certificate nRQF Level 7

Yildiz Technical University

2003-2007 | Istanbul Bachalor of Mechanical Engineering UK ENIC Certificate nRQF Level 6

PROJECTS

E-Commerce Website

A commercial product for my own clients. It is a full stack project developed with Angular and Python/Django.

Store Manager App

A Front-End case study that coded in React. Users can benefit from cashier applications, product/category managment, and also report interface.